Wrege, Charles D. Papers 6012
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Management Pioneers Data on search for material.. (Box 15)
  - Data on Mgt. 261 Rutgers and Definitions of Mgt. and Albert Davis Class Notes 1961 (Box 15, Folder 59)
  - Human Relations 1958 Material (Box 15, Folder 60)
  - Miller Communications Letter on Taylor Photo - July 30, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 61)
  - The Incandescent Lamp, 1879-1900 (Box 15, Folder 62)
  - Data from Marvyn Scudder, Manual of Extinct or Obsolete Corporations 1926 (Vol 1) 1928 (Vol 2), 1926-1928 (Box 15, Folder 63)
  - Bureau of Personnel Administration Harrison S. Elliott, "Fundamental Objectives of Business Management" Dec. 13, 1928 (Box 15, Folder 64)
  - Leland H. Jenks "Early Phases of the Management Movement" Admin. Science Quarterly, 1959 (Box 15, Folder 65)
  - Private Business Schools - 1920 (Box 15, Folder 66)
  - MIS - Prior to 1924, 1973 (Box 15, Folder 67)
  - Chris Argyris, 1962 (Box 15, Folder 68)
- Manuscripts to Biography of Taylor, Myth and Reality by CD Wrege and R. Greenwood 1991 Pub. Complete copies of various drafts. Pre-Irwin edits.. (Box 16)
  - Daniel Wren Review of Taylor Book, 7/19/91 - Review of Taylor Book (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Flyer for Taylor Book 1991 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Pages 29-76 of Taylor Book - July 1987, Handwritten Copy (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Preface to Taylor Book 1991 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - References for GMI Booklet on Taylor, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - To: Ron Greenwood 1987 (on Taylor Book, Midvale Negatives) June 27 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Nelson's Book on Taylor, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Notes on Taylor at Midvale (for book) April 4, 1987 and June 9, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Manuscript of Taylor Book 3/26/89 Version, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Sept. 29, 1988 Version of Taylor Book (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Early Version of Taylor Book Manuscript - 81 pages (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Taylor Book, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - First Version of Taylor Book Manuscript on Word Processor, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Print-Out of Taylor Book Manuscript, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    Original print-out
  - Ron Greenwood Correspondence 1990 (Revision to Book) - Greenwood on Taylor Book MS (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Various Pages of Taylor Manuscript to be Revised 5/12/89 - Taylor Book MS, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Taylor Book Manuscript (pages 29D-64) 4/27/89 Version, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Taylor Book Manuscript Version 5/2/89 (pages 29 D, 29 E, 30-72), 1989 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - 1866 Landownership and Midvale Steel Site - Use for Taylor Book - Butcher Steel 1866 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Ron Greenwood on Archives at Academy on Taylor Book 1991 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - James A. Wright Data (Related to F.W. Taylor Phila) Use for Taylor Book - Wright 1991, 1871-1876 (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Article on Eads Bridge Technology and Culture - Use for Taylor Book, Eads Bridge Butcher Steel, 1874 (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Data on F.W. Taylor at Phillips Exeter - Use for Taylor Book, Taylor-Exeter, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - Midvale Data for Taylor Book, 1867-1989 (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - Copies of Cards of Midvale Steel Showing Large Negatives Whose Location is Unknown as of March 15, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - Brooklyn Bridge, 1879-1882 (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - Taylor Manuscript - 4/1/89 Version, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - Taylor Book MS Changes, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 28)
  - Misc. Pages from Early Version of Taylor Book (pp. 4, 10, 11, 12, 13-17) 1989 (Box 16, Folder 29)
  - March 26, 1989 Version of Taylor Book (Box 16, Folder 30)
  - References for Taylor Book - Pages 148-157, June 6, 1989 Taylor Book MS (Box 16, Folder 31)
  - Pages 76B and 76Z of FW Taylor Manuscript 6/21/89, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 32)
  - Taylor Book Pages Sept. 4, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 33)
  - Taylor Book Pages Changed 10/29/90, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 34)
  - Taylor Manuscript Pages, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 35)
  - Taylor Book Pages, 1988 (Box 16, Folder 36)
  - Various Pages of Taylor Manuscript 1989 (Box 16, Folder 37)
  - Taylor MS Pages, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 38)
  - Taylor Book Manuscript, Page 153 to End, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 39)
  - Taylor MS, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 40)
  - Revised Pages to Taylor Manuscript 4/15/89, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 41)
  - Data on Tabor and Link-Belt for Taylor Book, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 42)
  - Photo Enlargements of Taylor Midvale 4/5/89, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 43)
  - Taylor Book (Box 16, Folder 44)
  - Misc. Taylor Biography Pages, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 45)
  - Taylor MS Pages, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 46)
- More of above including letters between CD Wrege and R. Greenwood about rewrites and reorganization.. (Box 17)
  - C.D. Wrege "Antecedents of Organizational Behavior" Dr. E.E. Southard and Mary C. Jarrett, "The Mental Hygiene of Industry" 1913-1920, Proceedings Academy of Mgt. 1979, 1913-1979 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Transparencies of Ernest Southard Outline of Mental Hygiene in Industry Book, 1918 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - C.D. Wrege - Medical Men and Scientific Management (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - C.D. Wrege - A Pioneer Mgt. Information System for Hospitals: The End Result System 1911-1918, 10/15/82, 1982 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - "Efficient Management of Hospitals" Manuscript, 1980 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Fighting for the Efficient Management of Hospitals, 1982 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Original Copy of "Pioneer Efforts to Introduce the 'Mental Hygiene' of Employees into Industry: 1913-1920" - 1987, Medical Men and Mgt. (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Letter from Duncan Neuhauser 11/29/88 on Codman, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Fighting for the Efficient Mgt. of Hospitals - Academy of Mgt. 1980 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Pages from Boston Paper on Taylor - Southard, etc., 1983 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence with Richard Wolfe of Harvard Medical School on Southard and Gilbreth Brain 1978-79, 1919-1979 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Richard Wolfe to CD Wrege on Southard Papers 10/29/78, 1978 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Copy of Letter to Richard Wolfe of Harvard on Southard 6/7/79, 1979 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Richard Wolfe Letters 1979 (Archivist, Harvard Medical School) (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Richard Wolfe Letters (on Dr. Southard) 1979 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Copy of Letter to Richard Wolfe of Harvard Medical School on Gilbreth and Hospitals 1/27/1980 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Richard Wolfe Letters 1980 (Countway Library Harvard) (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Dr. Southard Material from Countway Library 10/21/78, 1918-1919 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Extra Southard Transparencies (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence with Reverend William Gay (20 Hemlock Court, Springboro, Ohio 45066) on Southard Papers - 1979 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Biographer of Dr. Southard: Frederick Gay - Obituary of July 14, 1939 and Will Drawn 12/8/1930 - Southard, 1930-1979 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Dr. Gay Photo for N. File - Benday Screen 1979 - Southard and Medical Men and Mgt. (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Southard Search 1978, 1939-1978 (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - Copies of Dr. Southard Letters to 1919 (Originals Given by C.D.W. to Harvard Medical Library), 1919-1939 (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - Copies of Original Dr. Ernest Southard and Dr. Gay Papers 1980 (Originals Given to Countway Medical Library by C.D. Wrege), 1916- 1980 (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - Frederick Gay - Letters on Southard Book Open Mind, 1938 - Copies Given to Countway Medical Library Boston in 1980 by CDW) - Southard, Gay, 1938-1939 (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - Copies of Letters to Frederick Gay from Simon Flexner 1935 - on Early Ernest Southard Letters (Originals Given to Harvard Medical School, CDW) - 1935 Southard, 1916-1983 (Box 17, Folder 27)
  - Data on Alfred D. Flinn (from Frederick Gay's Papers from His Son 1980) - Southard, 1935-1936 (Box 17, Folder 28)
  - Southard Paper from Gay Files, 1920-1935 (Box 17, Folder 29)
  - Southard - Gay Prospective List 1928 (Box 17, Folder 30)
  - Southard Data, 1918-1935 (Box 17, Folder 31)
  - Copies of Letters on Southard in Gay Papers, 1916-1935 (Box 17, Folder 32)
  - Gay's Search for Southard's Papers, 1920-1938 (Box 17, Folder 33)
  - Southard - Gay Data Addresses, etc., 1915-1939 (Box 17, Folder 34)
    Copies of original documents and originals (booklets)
  - Data on People Who Knew Southard and Dr. Gay (Box 17, Folder 35)
  - Photos of Dr. Frederick Gay - Author of Open Mind Book on Dr. Southard 1993 (Box 17, Folder 36)
    Envelope with photos
  - January 16, 1979 - Letter to Reverend William Gay on Southard (Box 17, Folder 37)
  - The Open Mind, Frederick Gay (Box 17, Folder 38)
  - Dr. E.E. Southard Death Notice 2/9/1920 (Box 17, Folder 39)
  - Elmer Southard Death Certificate - February 8, 1920 (Box 17, Folder 40)
  - Southard Biography - Southard Data to File, 1914-1978 (Box 17, Folder 41)
  - Dr. Ernest Southard Poems - Originals Donated to Harvard Medical Library, 1919 (Box 17, Folder 42)
  - Southard's Projected Books and Papers in Open Mind pp. 282-283 (Box 17, Folder 43)
  - Copies of Ernest Southard Poems - (Not Dated, Originals Given by C.D. Wrege to Harvard Medical School), 1919 (Box 17, Folder 44)
  - Karl Menninger Letter on Southard Letters 8/28/79, 1979 (Box 17, Folder 45)
  - Dr. Southard Data, 1920 (Box 17, Folder 46)
  - Data on Yerkes and Dr. Southard - From J. Reid 7/31/79, 1979 (Box 17, Folder 47)
  - Dr. E.E. Southard on Industrial Accident Cases - BLS #248, 1917 (Box 17, Folder 48)
  - Southard - References in Files of the Permanent Charity Fund - Boston, 1918-19, 1978 (Box 17, Folder 49)
  - Southard Data in Permanent Charity Fund Files and Death Certificate NYC 2/8/1920 (Box 17, Folder 50)
  - Southard - 1918 Talk Before Mining Engineers Trans. Of Amer. Inst. Mining, Metallurgical and Petroleum Eng., Vol. LIX, No. 1, 1918 (Box 17, Folder 51)
  - Southard Articles on Mental Hygiene of Industry, 1917-1920 (Box 17, Folder 52)
  - Southard on Doctoral Efficiency 1919 (Box 17, Folder 53)
  - On Mental Hygiene and Industry and F.S. Lee, National Research Council - June 13, 1919 (Box 17, Folder 54)
  - Letter to Dr. Southard, May 19, 1919 on Psychology of Industry (Box 17, Folder 55)
  - Southard Letter to Thomas Salmon, National Committee for Mental Hygiene - 1919 - On Mental Hygiene in Industry (Box 17, Folder 56)
    Transparencies of original document
  - Dr. Ernest Southard on Psych in Social Work - June 13, 1919 (from Smith College Archives - Jarett Papers) (Box 17, Folder 57)
  - Southard on "Artistic Experience" Read at the Charaka Club, NY 11/19/1919 (Box 17, Folder 58)
  - E.E. Southard Will, 1978 (Box 17, Folder 59)
  - The Kingdom of Evils By Southard (1922), 1922-1975 (Box 17, Folder 60)
  - Review of Southard's Kingdom of Evils - NY Times Jan. 21, 1923 (Box 17, Folder 61)
  - Southard Bibliography from Kingdom of Evils, 1922 (Box 17, Folder 62)
  - John B. Blake Hist. of Medicine Div., 1978 (Box 17, Folder 63)
  - Data on Dr. Ernest Southard 1978 - Southard (Box 17, Folder 64)
  - Southard and Lee - Members of NRC 1919, at Columbia University 1979 (Box 17, Folder 65)
  - Robert Valentine Data, 1922 (Box 17, Folder 66)
  - Correspondence with Harley Holden of Harvard (on Dr. Richard Cabot) 1978 (Box 17, Folder 67)
  - Data on Myrtelle Moore Canavan, Born in St. Johns, Michigan 1879, Died in Boston August 26, 1953, Jl of the Amer. Medical Assoc. 1953, p. 1295 (Box 17, Folder 68)
  - Data on Dr. Myrtelle Canavan and Dr. Southard, 1949 (Box 17, Folder 69)
  - Dr. Myrtelle May Canavan Died 8/1/53, 1953 (Box 17, Folder 70)
  - E.E. Southard Brain Study 1925 (Box 17, Folder 71)
  - Southard Brain Study 1925 (Box 17, Folder 72)
  - Study of Einstein's Brain and Lenin's Brain from "The Stuff of Genius" NY Times Magazine, July 28, 1985 - use for Dr. Southard 1985 (Box 17, Folder 73)
  - Copies of Dr. Gay's Letters with Louise Nicholl and Myrtelle Canavan 1934-35, 1934-1935 (Box 17, Folder 74)
  - Addresses of Canavan, Goodrich, and Gibbs Families (use for Medical Men and Mgt.), 1916-1938 (Box 17, Folder 75)
  - Data from Who was Who on Myrtelle Canavan and Elmer Southard, 1949 (Box 17, Folder 76)
  - Robert Dickinson, "The New 'Efficiency' Systems and Their Bearing on Gynelogical Analysis" American Jl of Obstetrics, Dec. 1914, Plus Letter to Codman on Gilbreth 11/21/1913, 1913-1914 (Box 17, Folder 77)
  - Robert Dickinson on Hospitals, Taylor Soc. Bul. Oct. 1917, 1918 (Box 17, Folder 78)
  - Dr. Robert Dickinson Articles on Standardization of Surgery 1914, 1905, 1905-1914 (Box 17, Folder 79)
  - Robert Dickinson, July, Dec. 1914 on The New "Efficiency" Systems (Box 17, Folder 80)
  - Robert L. Dickinson "New Efficiency Systems," American Jl of Obstetrics, Dec. 1914 (Box 17, Folder 81)
  - Hospital Efficiency - 1914 Dickinson - Gilbreth - "Hospital Methods Make Surgery Costly" - NY Times Aug. 7, 1921, 1914-1921 (Box 17, Folder 82)
  - Efficiency Surveys of Hospitals 1922 (Box 17, Folder 83)
  - Individuals and Organizations Concerned with Efficiency of Hospitals 1910-1920, 1980 (Box 17, Folder 84)
  - Dental Archives 1980, 1917 (Box 17, Folder 85)
  - Medical Men and Mgt. Articles, 1914 (Box 17, Folder 86)
  - Dr. Victor Anderson Search 1984 (Relate to Southard), 1960-1984 (Box 17, Folder 87)
  - Data on Management of Hospitals - Operating Room Colors, etc., 1914-1976 (Box 17, Folder 88)
- Midvale Steel Co. plans for book, intended not produced. Early history of the Company. Information on the William Butcher Steel Works. Original deeds.. (Box 18)
  - Midvale Steel in Newspapers 1920-1922, 1930-1940, 1920-1940 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Steel Worker - Jan. 1919, Midvale (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Collection of Notes for C. Wrege Book on History of Midvale 1991 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Work Sites Book, 1986 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Copies of Midvale Steel Safety Bulletins Showing Photos of Items in Midvale Negative Files 1996, 1937-1953 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Midvale Data on City of Phila 6/12/85 - and 1991 Plans for Book (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Data on Plans for Book on Midvale - Starting April 16, 1991 - Includes Sheet Outline of Plans - Metz Letter of 4-22-91 - Midvale Book Data, 1987-1991 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - W.D. Roberts - Box 44 Lynchburg, VA 24505 - on Bachman Painting of Midvale - Midvale Book Data, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Notes for History of Midvale Book - (MS due June 1993), 1961 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - 1935 Clippings on Midvale - For Midvale Book, 1883-1935 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    Copy and original documents (envelope)
  - Richard Strassberg April 27, 1991 (on Midvale Book) (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Midvale Forms (by Taylor) for Midvale Book 10/24/91 - Midvale Book, 1951-1991 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Walter D. Robert - Box 44 Lynchburg, VA 24508 (Painting of Midvale) - June 15, 1990, Midvale-Taylor (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Some Thoughts on Area Around Midvale Steel Co. 2-19-88 (4 pages) (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Letter from Lance Metz Oct. 18, 1991 (On Old Steel Terms) - Use For Midvale Book, 1915-1991 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Data on 8x10 Midvale Photos and Negatives (Location Unknown) 1990 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Fall Research Projects (Questions on Midvale) 1988, 1987-1988 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - F.W. Taylor's Work at Midvale in Copley's Biography 9-17-83 (one page and two pages), 1983 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Taylor Patent 400,143 - Forging Mechanism 400,143 3/26/89 - Used at Midvale, 1889 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Rifled Cannon Data at Annapolis and West Point, 1880-1889 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Civil War Guns - Lincoln and The Tools of War - Use for Midvale Background, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Federal Report of 1883 on Midvale Guns (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - City of Phila Airport, June 12, 1985 - On Background of Midvale - Heppenstall Co. - Good to Accompany Negatives of Midvale for Cornell - CDW June 24, 1995 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Data on People of Midvale to Check in Gopsill's 1989 - Midvale (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - Canal Museum Symposium - Paper on Midvale (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - Personal Chronologies at Midvale, Midvale and Taylor Book, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - Personal Chronologies and the Midvale Company, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - Personnel Chronologies - Midvale Co. (Howard Myer Papers), 1937 (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - Officers of William Butcher Steel Works - Philadelphia (1866-1890) (Box 18, Folder 29)
  - Jean Myers Correspondence and Photos of Midvale Officers, 1990-1991 (Box 18, Folder 30)
    Original documents and photos in envelope
  - Books on Philadelphia in NY Public Library 1987 (Box 18, Folder 31)
  - Safety Bulletin, Midvale Steel Co., 1914 (Box 18, Folder 32)
  - Rifled Cannon Data (on Midvale) 1987, 1895-1987 (Box 18, Folder 33)
  - Manuscript of History of Midvale Steel and The Work of F.W. Taylor, August 8, 1991 (Box 18, Folder 34)
  - G. Aertren, History of Midvale 1914-1915 (Box 18, Folder 35)
  - Midvale Steel Bulletin - Vol. 2 #1, Jan. 1915 (G. Aertsen History) (Box 18, Folder 36)
  - 1917 History of Midvale Steel, 1917-1989 (Box 18, Folder 37)
  - Midvale and Its Pioneers - Nalle, 1947 (Box 18, Folder 38)
  - Richard T. Nalle Jr. 915 Mt. Pleasant Rd., PA 19010, 215-525-4589, 1948-1991 (Box 18, Folder 39)
  - Richard Nalle Data (President of Midvale Steel 1946), 1917-1948 (Box 18, Folder 40)
  - Richard T. Nalle Data 1991 (Box 18, Folder 41)
  - Data on Richard Nalle of Midvale Steel and His Death in House Fire Jan. 29, 1983 - Nalle (Box 18, Folder 42)
  - Midvale Steel (1951 History) (Box 18, Folder 43)
  - 1957 History of Midvale by Howard C. Myers Junior (Box 18, Folder 44)
    Original documents (envelope) and copies
  - Two Pages of Notes on Midvale History from H.C. Myers Jr. (Box 18, Folder 45)
  - "Midvale - Heppenstall Company" Acquire Midvale in 1955 (December), See Article in Greater Philadelphia Magazine Dec 1957, pp. 20-22 (Now the Park Corporation 4200 Wissahicken Ave. Phila) (Box 18, Folder 46)
  - Midvale Steel Works in Manufacturers and Manufacturers of Pennsylvania of 19th Century, Galaxy Pub. Co. 1975 (Box 18, Folder 47)
  - Midvale History, 1942 (Box 18, Folder 48)
  - New York Times, 1866-1974 (Box 18, Folder 49)
  - Gopsill's Directory 1871 on William Butcher Steel Works p. 481 (Box 18, Folder 50)
  - Gopsill's City Directory, Phila 1876 for Taylor Book - Taylor (Box 18, Folder 51)
  - Deed to Land at Midvale Steel Land - Nov. 1866, Butcher Deed to Midvale Land, Nov. 1866 - Midvale (Box 18, Folder 52)
  - Betty Butcher Topp (Related to William Butcher Jr.) 1989 (Box 18, Folder 53)
  - William Butcher Jr. and Thomas Shaw - Patent 65,339, June 4, 1867 (Box 18, Folder 54)
    Original documents (fragile)
  - Thomas Shaw, Engineer for Butcher Steel Works, Born 4-5-1838, Died Jan 19, 1901 - Power Hammer Patent 2-27-1866 Midvale, 1901- 1989 (Box 18, Folder 55)
  - Thomas Shaw and Obed Hussey (Related to Midvale Taylor) Midvale (Box 18, Folder 56)
  - Geoffrey Trovedale, Giants of Sheffield Steel on William Butcher of Sheffield, England, Not the William Butcher of Midvale, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 57)
  - Richard Carlson 4/17/89 on "Butcher's" in England - Taylor Book, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 58)
  - Howard Butcher III, Died June 19, 1991, Sons: Howard IV, McBee (Bryn Mawe), Johnathan - Elverson, PA (Box 18, Folder 59)
  - History of Baldwin Locomotive Works - (on W. Butcher), Steel Castings, 1831-1920 (Box 18, Folder 60)
  - Butcher Genealogical Data from Society of Friends 11/22/88, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 61)
  - William Butcher in Lewistown, PA 1870-71 (From Bernice Golla - 101 Nickel Ave, Sayreville, NJ 08872, 855-4434) 1991 (Box 18, Folder 62)
  - Independent Research William Butcher Jr. 1991 (Box 18, Folder 63)
    Blue folder with original document
  - William Butcher in England, Research by Radha Jagannathan August 1988 Midvale (Box 18, Folder 64)
  - William Butcher Jr. Data 1991 (Box 18, Folder 65)
  - Charles A. Brinley, F.W. Taylor and William Butcher in Gopsill's Phila Directory 1880-1889 - Taylor Book (Box 18, Folder 66)
  - Midvale, William Butcher Jr., Radha Jagannathan, William Butcher Project Summer 1988 (Box 18, Folder 67)
  - Census of 1871 Listing William Butcher, Wife, and 2 Children (Box 18, Folder 68)
  - Data on "Butcher" in Phila 1988 - For Taylor Book, 1861-1988 (Box 18, Folder 69)
  - William Butcher Junior Search, 1830-1834 (Box 18, Folder 70)
  - William Butcher Jr. and William Butcher Steel Works in Gopsill's (by years), 1991 (Box 18, Folder 71)
  - Radha Jagannathan's Research into William Butcher Jr. 1988 - Taylor Book (Box 18, Folder 72)
  - Deed Search Philadelphia for Taylor 1988 and Midvale (Box 18, Folder 73)
  - Deed C. Colkett to William Butcher Jr. Nov. 16, 1866 - Midvale (Box 18, Folder 74)
  - Coffin Colkett Data (Sold Land to William Butcher) (Box 18, Folder 75)
  - W. Butcher to W. Butcher Steel Works, Deed 8/20/ 1867 JTO Book 146 pp. 305-308 (Box 18, Folder 76)
  - William Butcher Jr. and Annie His Wife, Deed to William Butcher Steel Works - August 20, 1867, $175,00 (Taylor Midvale) - William Butcher to Will. Butcher Steel Works (Box 18, Folder 77)
  - Gregory Vascimini Letters 1988 on Search for William Butcher Jr. in Philadelphia - Use for Taylor Book (Box 18, Folder 78)
  - Deeds, Midvale, C.D. Wrege, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 79)
    Blue folder with documents
  - Deed Search - W. Butcher Land in Germantown, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 80)
  - Justice Family in McElroy's Phila. Directory 1850, 1860 (related to Midvale) (Box 18, Folder 81)
  - W. Butcher Steel Co. Tool Mark (Box 18, Folder 82)
  - Coffin Colket Deed to William Butcher Jr. Nov. 16, 1866 (Site of Midvale Steel) - See Letter from Kimberly James 4/12/91, 1866- 1991 (Box 18, Folder 83)
  - William Butcher Jr. Deed JTO Book 2, pp. 345-49 11/16/1866 and Deed JTO Book 146, pp. 305-308 8/20/67 Midvale, 1866- 1867 (Box 18, Folder 84)
  - Charles E. Smith - President of Philadelphia and Reading RR 1869 (Provided Money to Purchase Land for Butcher Steel Works), 1869- 1988 (Box 18, Folder 85)
  - Gowen, The Reading RR (Use for Colket and Butcher 1866) (Box 18, Folder 86)
  - Various Butcher Data (Howard and William) Midvale 1988 (Box 18, Folder 87)
  - Deed Data on Site of Link-Bolt Engineering, Hydraulic Works - Phila, 1859-1953 (Box 18, Folder 88)
  - Alfred Jenks and Jenks and Sons Machine Works at Bridesburg Sect. of Phila (1877, Phillip Justice Mgt. Guns and Bayonets in Civil War) (Box 18, Folder 89)
  - Gantt Data 1988 (Box 18, Folder 90)
  - Midvale Company: Newspaper Articles 1954 (Box 18, Folder 91)
- Midvale - Huston Suit 1870-80s. He put up a lot of money for the company and was cheated out of it. A lot of information about the Company, the Facer Patent Suit and on Midvale in general.. (Box 19)
  - Data on Krupp (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Gun Foundry Board Data 1883 (and Midvale), 1883-1988 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Armor Plate on Midvale - 1916 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - National Archives and Rifled Cannon - For Taylor Book 1987 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Data on Built-Up, Breach-Loading Rifled Cannon - 1881 Midvale and Foundry Museum Letter 1987 - For Taylor Book (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Midvale Armor Test 1901-1904 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Midvale Armor Contract Data 1892-Onward (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Armor Plate in The NY Times 8/19/1892 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Krupp vs. Midvale Case 1908 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Data on Armor Plating Iron Age 1900-1909, 1900-1908 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Fried Krupp Ag v. Midvale Steel Co. (Appeal Oct. 11, 1911 Federal Reporter 191-pp.588-612 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Data on Open Hearth Furnace at Midvale July 21, 1871 (on Original Midvale Stationary from Howard C. Myers, Papers Attained July 1990) (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Rifled Cannon and Taylor - Midvale 1989, 1987-1989 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Data on Armor Mgt. (Midvale etc.) from NY Times 1892-1910, use for Midvale Book 11/9/91, 1892-1990 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - James Facer Suit Against Midvale - Circuit Court Eastern District PA 11-9-1888, 1888-1988 (Box 19, Folder 15)